Jonathan Vottero

3945 Pointe W Pl. Apt 212 Rapid City SD 57702 (605) 431-8682 votterojonathan@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Seeking a career where I can learn from experienced developers and contribute to the growth of a team. Computer Science degree with three years of professional experience in software development. Competent developing purpose driven full stack applications. Excited to learn new skills and domains.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer — Innovative System MAY 2020 - PRESENT

- Implemented and designed WPF configuration forms for end users.
- Converted legacy WinForms GUI's to WPF.
- Created Rich Text parsing software used to print custom messages and images.
- Sole maintainer of invoice generation app with integration to third-party financials software.
- Created custom msi installer using WiX Toolset.

.NET Software Intern — Innovative Systems MAY 2018 - MAY 2020

- Developed a C# & WPF application to visualize large amounts of modem data with up to six seconds of precision.
- Utilized .NET Blazor web assembly framework to create a web application to process billing for small municipal utilities companies.
- Practiced scrum and agile methodologies to deliver new features as part of a development team.

PROJECTS

Senior Design Data Entry Form And OCR Project Manager

- Led team in creating a software solution for a local company to expedite and automate data entry.
- Corresponded with our client to deliver an effective product and rapid bug fixes.
- Negotiated \$1000 per member payment for work that exceeded responsibilities of the academic project.

Senior Design USAF flight planning Project Manager

- Led team in creating a software solution for contact in the United States Air Force used to plan and schedule training flights.
- Made a sales presentation at a local business plan competition in front of a panel of investors.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Experienced:

C#, C++, SQL

Familiar:

Python, JAVA, HTML, CSS, Javascript

OTHER SKILLS

Technologies:

WPF, Blazor, Visual Studio, Git, Linux, Windows, Matlab

Processes:

Agile design, SOLID principles, SCRUM, OOP, TDD

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science South Dakota School of Mines & Technology Rapid City, SD 2015 - 2020

Graduated Cum Lade